Guide to the Robert Pinsky Papers
Department of Special Collections
- Series I. Correspondence
  - Subseries: General
    - T-Y, misc.
      - Worcester County Poetry Association, Inc. (c.1991) (Box 34, Folder 17)
      - Writers Exchange, Poets and Writers, Inc. 1988 Competition, reading at Cody's Books, Berkeley 34 17 The Writers Workshop (n.d.) (Box 34, Folder 17)
      - YM/YWHA, Philadelphia, David Slavitt (1987-1989) (Box 34, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous
      - miscellaneous notes and promotional materials: biographical sketches, book orders, student responses to readings, etc. (Box 34, Folder 18)
    - G-H, misc.
      - Dante's Inferno, captions (Box 36, Folder 1)
      - late Dante draft with changes to the text (Box 36, Folder 2)
      - Dante draft, notes to the text by Nicole Pinsky (Box 36, Folder 3)
      - Guggenheim Memorial Foundation (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - Halliday, Mark (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - L-M, misc.
      - Levine, Phil (Box 37, Folder 3)
      - Lewis (Winters), Janet (Box 37, Folder 3)
      - Logan, John (Box 37, Folder 3)
      - Lowell, Robert (Box 37, Folder 3)
      - unidentified, Penny and Robert (Box 37, Folder 3)
      - Marchant, Fred (Box 37, Folder 4)
      - Matthias, John (Box 37, Folder 4)
      - Moran, Pat (Box 37, Folder 4)
      - Mazur, Gail (Box 37, Folder 4)
      - McClatchy, J. D. (Sandy) (Box 37, Folder 5)
      - McHugh, Heather (Box 37, Folder 5)
      - Meredith, William (Box 37, Folder 5)
      - Mitchell, Stephen (Box 37, Folder 5)
      - Molesworth, Charles (Box 37, Folder 5)
      - Muller, Laura (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - N-W, misc.
      - Napa Valley Poetry Conference (Dave Evans) (Box 37, Folder 6)
      - Raab, Lawrence (Box 37, Folder 7)
      - Random House (Johnathan Galassi) (Box 37, Folder 7)
      - Raritan a quarterly review (Donna K. Green) (Box 37, Folder 7)
      - Ray, Dave (Box 37, Folder 7)
      - Romanov, Peter (Box 37, Folder 7)
      - Roth, Philip (Box 37, Folder 7)
      - Ryan, Michael (Box 37, Folder 7)
      - University of Illinois (Gene W. Ruoff) (Box 37, Folder 7)
      - University of Montana (William Pitt Root) (Box 37, Folder 7)
      - Warren, Rosanna (Box 37, Folder 8)
      - Williamson, Alan (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Subseries: Correspondence with relatives
    - Bernice (aunt) (Box 3a, Folder 26)
    - Carol, David, Jessica (Box 3a, Folder 26)
    - Gail (cousin) (Box 3a, Folder 26)
    - Milford Pinsky (father) (Box 3a, Folder 26)
    - Rose (grandmother) (Box 3a, Folder 26)
    - Silvia (mother) (Box 3a, Folder 26)
    - Susan Edelmann (sister) (Box 3a, Folder 26)
    - Zadee (grandfather) (Box 3a, Folder 26)
    - Unidentified, incl: "B," Bob, "Cap and Honey," "D and A" (Dave and Ann), Marcia, Margery (Sabin?), Nate, Pam, Shobhana, Tom (Box 3a, Folder 27)
  - Subseries: New Republic Correspondence (1)
    - A-F, misc.
      - Beatty, Jack (Box 3.2, Folder 1)
      - Berg, Steve (American Poetry Review) (Box 3.2, Folder 1)
      - Bidart, Frank (Box 3.2, Folder 1)
      - Bogen, Don (Box 3.2, Folder 1)
      - Bromwich, David (Box 3.2, Folder 1)
      - Clampitt, Amy (Box 3.2, Folder 2)
      - Collier, Michael (Box 3.2, Folder 2)
      - Corn, Alfred (Box 3.2, Folder 2)
      - Crave, Doug (Box 3.2, Folder 2)
      - Cunningham, J.V. (Jim) (Box 3.2, Folder 2)
      - Davie, Donald (Box 3.2, Folder 3)
      - Dennis, Carl (Box 3.2, Folder 3)
      - Dickey, James (Box 3.2, Folder 3)
      - Eberhart, Richard (Box 3.2, Folder 4)
      - Feldman, Irving (Box 3.2, Folder 4)
      - Ferry, David (Box 3.2, Folder 4)
      - Fields, Ken (Box 3.2, Folder 4)
      - Flanders, Jane (Box 3.2, Folder 4)
      - Fussell, Paul (Box 3.2, Folder 4)
    - G-L, misc.
      - Gibbons, Reginald (Box 3.2, Folder 5)
      - Goldensohn, Barry (Box 3.2, Folder 5)
      - Grossman, Allen (Box 3.2, Folder 5)
      - Guerard, Maclin (Box 3.2, Folder 5)
      - Hadas, Rachel (Box 3.2, Folder 5)
      - Halliday, Mark (Box 3.2, Folder 5)
      - Hammer, Larry (Box 3.2, Folder 5)
      - Heaney, Seamus (Box 3.2, Folder 5)
      - Hecht, Anthony (Box 3.2, Folder 5)
      - Hirsch, Edward (Box 3.2, Folder 5)
      - Hoffman, Daniel (Box 3.2, Folder 6)
      - Hollander, John (Box 3.2, Folder 6)
      - Honig, Edwin (Box 3.2, Folder 6)
      - Howard, Richard (Box 3.2, Folder 6)
      - Hugo, Richard (Box 3.2, Folder 6)
      - Hulbert, Ann (Box 3.2, Folder 7)
      - Kenyon, Jane (Box 3.2, Folder 8)
      - Kinnell, Galway (Box 3.2, Folder 8)
      - Kinzie, Mary (Box 3.2, Folder 8)
      - Krok, Peter (Box 3.2, Folder 8)
      - Lea, Sydney (Box 3.2, Folder 9)
      - Leithauser, Brad (Box 3.2, Folder 9)
      - Lesser, Rita (Box 3.2, Folder 9)
      - Lewis (Winters), Janet (Box 3.2, Folder 9)
      - Lipsitz, Lou (Box 3.2, Folder 9)
      - Lockwood, Margo (Box 3.2, Folder 9)
      - Louthan, Robert (Box 3.2, Folder 9)
    - M-R, misc.
      - Malizia, Michael (Box 3.2, Folder 10)
      - Mazur, Gail (Box 3.2, Folder 10)
      - McClatchy, J.D. ("Sandy") (Box 3.2, Folder 10)
      - Merfeld, Patricia (Box 3.2, Folder 10)
      - Merrill, James (Box 3.2, Folder 10)
      - Morgan, Frederick (Box 3.2, Folder 10)
      - Nemerov, Howard (Box 3.2, Folder 11)
      - Oates, Joyce Carol (Box 3.2, Folder 11)
      - Olds, Sharon (Box 3.2, Folder 11)
      - Parini, Jay (Box 3.2, Folder 12)
      - Pastan, Linda (Box 3.2, Folder 12)
      - Peseroff, Joyce (Box 3.2, Folder 12)
      - Pollens, David (Box 3.2, Folder 12)
      - Rees, Ennis (Box 3.2, Folder 13)
      - Ridland, John (Box 3.2, Folder 13)
      - Rinaldi, Nicholas (Box 3.2, Folder 13)
      - Rosenberg, L. M. (Box 3.2, Folder 13)
      - Rosten, Norman (Box 3.2, Folder 13)
      - Ryan, Michael (Box 3.2, Folder 13)
    - S-Z, misc.
      - Sacks, Peter (Box 3.2, Folder 14)
      - Sadoff, Ira (Box 3.2, Folder 14)
      - Schwartz, Lloyd (Box 3.2, Folder 14)
      - Shore, Jane (Box 3.2, Folder 14)
      - Simon, Greg (Box 3.2, Folder 14)
      - Sofield, David (Box 3.2, Folder 14)
      - Sommer, Jason (Box 3.2, Folder 14)
      - Strand, Mark (Box 3.2, Folder 14)
      - Updike, John (Box 3.2, Folder 15)
      - Weiss, Ted and Renée (Box 3.2, Folder 15)
      - Williams, C.K. (Charlie) (Box 3.2, Folder 15)
      - Williamson, Alan (Box 3.2, Folder 15)
      - Wilner, Eleanor (Box 3.2, Folder 15)
      - Winters, Anne (Box 3.2, Folder 15)
      - Wolf, Douglas (Box 3.2, Folder 15)
      - Wolff, David (Box 3.2, Folder 15)
      - Zebrun, Gary (Box 3.2, Folder 15)
    - Unidentified
      - Unidentified and Miscellaneous: TNR rejection ships for Pinsky poetry, Alice, Stephen [Dunn?]) (Box 3.2, Folder 16)
    - A-G, misc.
      - Anthony, Frank (Box 19a, Folder 1)
      - Blumenthal, Michael (Box 19a, Folder 1)
      - Bly, Robert (Box 19a, Folder 1)
      - Booth, Philip (Box 19a, Folder 1)
      - Brodsky (Box 19a, Folder 1)
      - Collier, Michael (Box 19a, Folder 1)
      - Connellan, Leo (Box 19a, Folder 1)
      - Dennis, Carl (Box 19a, Folder 2)
      - Dobyns, Stephen (Box 19a, Folder 2)
      - Galassi, Jonathan (Box 19a, Folder 3)
      - Gorczynski, Renata (translation of work by Adam Zagajewski) (Box 19a, Folder 3)
      - Goldensohn, Barry (Box 19a, Folder 3)
      - Greger, Debora (Box 19a, Folder 3)
      - Gunn, Thom (Box 19a, Folder 3)
    - H-L, misc.
      - Hadas, Rachel (Box 19a, Folder 4)
      - Harrison, Jeffrey (Box 19a, Folder 4)
      - Hollander, John (Box 19a, Folder 4)
      - Helfgott Hyett, Barbara (Box 19a, Folder 4)
      - Hirsch, Edward (Box 19a, Folder 4)
      - Hulbert, Ann (Box 19a, Folder 4)
      - Keeley, Edmund ("Mike") (translation of poems by Yannis Ritsos) (Box 19a, Folder 5)
      - Klement, Vera (re: Robert Hass) (Box 19a, Folder 5)
      - Korson, Michael (Box 19a, Folder 5)
      - Lea, Sydney (Box 19a, Folder 6)
      - Leithauser, Brad (Box 19a, Folder 6)
      - Lewis (Winters), Janet (Box 19a, Folder 6)
      - Logan, John (Box 19a, Folder 6)
    - M-R, misc.
      - Mathis, Cleopatra (Box 19a, Folder 7)
      - Mazur, Gail (Box 19a, Folder 7)
      - McHugh, Heather (Box 19a, Folder 7)
      - McPherson, Sandra (Box 19a, Folder 7)
      - Niditch, B. Z. (Box 19a, Folder 8)
      - Pack, Robert (Box 19a, Folder 8)
      - Pastan, Linda (Box 19a, Folder 8)
      - Parini, Jay (Box 19a, Folder 8)
      - Prunty, Wyatt (Box 19a, Folder 8)
      - Ratushinskaya, Irina (Box 19a, Folder 9)
      - Ribolow, Philip (Box 19a, Folder 2)
      - Rosen, Michael (Box 19a, Folder 9)
    - S-Z, misc.
      - Sacks, Peter (Box 19a, Folder 10)
      - Salter, Mary Jo (Box 19a, Folder 10)
      - Seth, Vikram (Box 19a, Folder 10)
      - Shapiro, Alan (Box 19a, Folder 10)
      - Shore, Jane (Box 19a, Folder 10)
      - Smith, Dave (Box 19a, Folder 10)
      - Updike, John (Box 19a, Folder 11)
      - Walcott, Derek (Box 19a, Folder 11)
      - Waterhouse, Elizabeth (Box 19a, Folder 11)
      - Wormter, Baron (Box 19a, Folder 11)
      - Yamamoto, Traise (Box 19a, Folder 11)
    - Unidentified
      - Unidentified (incl. Lewis, Paul) (Box 19a, Folder 12)
  - Subseries: New Republic Correspondence (2):Poetry by various authors
    - A-G, misc.
      - Collier, Michael (Box 19a, Folder 13)
      - Corn, Alfred (Box 19a, Folder 13)
      - Dennis, Carl (Box 19a, Folder 13)
      - Goldensohn, Barry (Box 19a, Folder 14)
      - Greger, Debora (Box 19a, Folder 14)
    - H-L, misc.
      - Halley, Anne (Box 19a, Folder 14)
      - Harrison, Jeffrey (Box 19a, Folder 14)
      - Henrie, Carol (Box 19a, Folder 14)
      - Hirsch, Edward (Box 19a, Folder 14)
      - Hollander, John (Box 19a, Folder 14)
      - Keeley, Edmund "Mike" (translation of work by Yannis Ritsos) (Box 19a, Folder 15)
      - Kenyon, Jane (Box 19a, Folder 15)
      - Korson, Michael (Box 19a, Folder 15)
      - Leithauser, Brad (Box 19a, Folder 15)
      - Lewis (Winters), Janet (Box 19a, Folder 15)
    - M-P, misc.
      - Mathis, Cleopatra (Box 19a, Folder 16)
      - McClatchy, J.D. (Box 19a, Folder 16)
      - McHugh, Heather (Box 19a, Folder 16)
      - Milosz, Czeslaw (translated by Robert Pinsky, Robert Hass) (Box 19a, Folder 16)
      - Pack, Robert (Box 19a, Folder 17)
      - Pastan, Linda (Box 19a, Folder 17)
      - Peck, John (Box 19a, Folder 17)
      - Powell, Jim (Box 19a, Folder 17)
      - Prunty, Wyatt (Box 19a, Folder 17)
    - Q-Z, misc.
      - Sacks, Peter (Box 19a, Folder 18)
      - Salter, Mary Jo (Box 19a, Folder 18)
      - Seth, Vikram (Box 19a, Folder 18)
      - Shapiro, Alan (Box 19a, Folder 19)
      - Shore, Jane (Box 19a, Folder 19)
      - Smith, Bruce (Box 19a, Folder 19)
      - Smith, Dave (Box 19a, Folder 19)
      - Soto, Garry (Box 19a, Folder 19)
      - Wagoner, David (Box 19a, Folder 20)
      - Walcott, Derek (Box 19a, Folder 20)
      - Williams, C.K. (Box 19a, Folder 20)
      - Williamson, Alan (Box 19a, Folder 20)
  - Subseries: Correspondence regarding Pinksy's translation of Dante's Inferno
    - Copies of Pinsky's Dante with comments, by:
      - Ferry, Anne (Box 33, Folder 15)
      - Ferry, David (Box 33, Folder 15)
      - Freccero, [?] (Box 33, Folder 15)
      - Galassi, Jonathan (Box 33, Folder 16)
      - Howard, Richard (Box 33, Folder 17)
      - McHugh, Heather (Box 33, Folder 18)
      - Rudman, Mark (Box 33, Folder 18)
      - Warren, Roseanna (Box 33, Folder 18)
      - Williamson, Alan (Box 33, Folder 18)
      - Writess, Anne (Box 33, Folder 18)
      - Unidentified/Miscellaneous (Box 33, Folder 19)
    - Notes (for publication) on Pinsky's Dante, by:
      - Albertini, S. (Box 33, Folder 20)
      - Mazur, Michael (Box 33, Folder 21)
      - Pinsky, Robert (translator's note to the text) (Box 33, Folder 21)
    - Dante Miscellaneous:
      - note (Box 33, Folder 22)
      - "Inferno Joe" comics (Box 33, Folder 22)
      - Dante study questions by R. Jacoff (Box 33, Folder 22)
- Series II. Poetry
  - Subseries: General
    - "The Changes" (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - "Clara and Benedict" (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - "The Cold" (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - "An Explanation of America" (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - "Fairyland" (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - "The Figured Wheel" (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - "Flowers" (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - "History of My Heart" (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - "History of My Heart", including correspondence with J.D. "Sandy" McClatchy (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - "Icicles" (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - "Memorial" (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - "Mr. Mintser" (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - "The New Saddhus" (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - "Poetry Editor" (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - "The Questions" (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Sadness And Happiness (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - "Salt Water" (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - The Separate Notebooks: Poems (trans. of Czeslaw Milosz by Pinsky) (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - "Song of Reasons" (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - "Song on Porcelain" (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - "Sonnet" (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - "Stanzas from Valéry" (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - "The Street" (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - "Two Reproductions for a Child" (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - "The Unseen" (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - "The Volume" (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - "The Want Bone" (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Poetry and the World drafts, with suggestions by Robert Hass (Box 19a, Folder 21)
    - Poetry and the World drafts, with suggestions by Stephen Mitchell (Box 19a, Folder 22)
    - American Poetry and American Life, drafts, with suggestions by Robert Hass (Box 19a, Folder 23)
    - American Poetry and American Life, proofs (Box 19a, Folder 24)
    - "Catatonic Song" (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - "A Christmas Wreath of Poems" (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - "Clara and Benedict" (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - "Closing Time: The Sequal to Catch-22" (book review) (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - "Control, Freedom, and the Appetite for Poetry" (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - "Creation According to Ovid" (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - "Dante Alighieri, Inventor of Horror" (translator's note) (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - "Dreaming of Deafness" (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - "Essay on Psychiatrists" (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - An Explanation of America (excerpt) (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - "Gerry Mulligan" (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - "Having it By Heart" (incomplete) (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - "The Heartmoss" (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - "Icicles" (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - "Impossible to Tell" (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - "In Berkeley" (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - "Lament for the Makers" (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - "The Lesson" (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - "Literary Visit to Poland" (Box 27, Folder 19)
    - "Mr. Mintser" (Box 27, Folder 20)
    - "A Note on Five Poems" (Box 27, Folder 21)
    - "Out of History" (Box 27, Folder 22)
    - "Poem with Refrains" (Box 27, Folder 23)
    - "Poetry and Pleasure" (Box 27, Folder 24)
    - "Portrait Sketches" ("A Room of People") (Box 27, Folder 25)
    - "Round" (Box 27, Folder 26)
    - "Soot" (Box 27, Folder 27)
    - "Street Dreamers" (Box 27, Folder 28)
    - "The Superb Lily" (Box 27, Folder 29)
    - "Three Charms for an Irish Photographer" (Box 27, Folder 30)
    - "Times and Places" (Box 27, Folder 31)
    - "The Tuning" (Box 27)
    - "The Uncreation" (Box 27, Folder 32)
    - "Voyage to the Moon" (Box 27, Folder 33)
    - The Want Bone (advance copy) (Box 27, Folder 34)
    - "What Why When How Who" and "Memoir" (Box 27, Folder 35)
    - The Wild Iris (Box 27, Folder 36)
    - Unidentified fragments (Box 27, Folder 37)
    - "On 'Eve Tempted by the Serpent'..." (Box 33, Folder 25)
    - "To Television" (Box 33, Folder 26)
    - "The City Dark" and Pinsky interview in Bostonia (1994-1995) (Box 34, Folder 19)
    - Columbia Lecture Series: "If You Could Write One Great Poem, What Would You Want It To Be About?" (1995) (Box 34, Folder 20)
    - Columbia Lecture Series: "Old Poetry, New Poetry" (1993) (Box 34, Folder 21)
    - Columbia Lecture Series: "Poetry and its Place" (1994) (Box 34, Folder 22)
    - Creation According to Ovid" in After Ovid; correspondence: Farrar, Strauss & Giroux, Inc., Jonathan Galassi, The Unterberg Poetry Center at the 92nd St. Y, Karl Kirchwey (1994) (Box 34, Folder 23)
    - Dante's Inferno, Canto II (1993) (Box 34, Folder 24)
    - Dante's Inferno, Canto XXVIII (n.d.) (Box 34, Folder 25)
    - Dante's Inferno, Canto XXXII; correspondence: Salt Hill Journal (Syracuse) (n.d.) (Box 34, Folder 26)
    - Dante's Inferno, proofs, book jacket; correspondence: Farrar, Strauss & Giroux, Inc., Jonathan Galassi; jacket for The Figured Wheel also enclosed (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - "Desecration of the Gravestone of Rose P. (1897-1924)" (Antiphony with "Church Monuments" by George Herbert) (n.d.) (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - "Desecration of the Gravestone of Rose P. (1897-1924)" proofs; correspondence: Wendy Lesser, The Three Penny Review (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - "Ice-Storm"; correspondence: The New Republic (1995) (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - "Impossible to Tell"; correspondence: Wendy Lesser, The Three Penny Review (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - "JM & EB" [James Merrill and Elizabeth Bishop] (n.d.) (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - "The Muse in the Machine" with comments by Louise Gluck (1995) (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - "Nerds, Technocrats and Enlightened Spirits" (1995) (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - "Ode to Meaning" (n.d.) (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - "Prose in the Poetry of William Carlos Williams" ["Prose and All"?]; correspondence: Parnassus, Herbert Leibowitz (1995) (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - "The Romantics and Us" lecture series/conference/anthology: "Skies of the City" by Pinsky; correspondence: University of Illinois at Chicago, Rutgers University Press (1988-1990) (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Sandeen, Ernest, Pinsky foreward to Can These Bones Live?; correspondence: John Matthias (1994) (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - "Technology and the Creative Imagination" (n.d.) (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - proofs of various poems for P.N. Review 100; correspondence: P.N. Review, Michael Schmidt; poems: "Shirt", "From the Childhood of Jesus", "The Day Dreamers", "The Want Bone"; "Poem with Refrains" (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - miscellaneous drafts, fragments and notes on manuscripts (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - Dante's Inferno, captions (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - late Dante draft with changes to the text (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Dante draft, notes to the text by Nicole Pinsky (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - "The Green Piano" (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - "Michael Mazur" (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - "Poem" (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - "The Ruins" (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - Dante's Inferno: galleys and correspondence with The Ecco Press Antaeus (Johnathan Galassi, Daniel Halpern); correspondence with Unterberg Poetry Center (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - Dante's Inferno: proofs of book design and map, correspondence with Farrar, Straus & Giroux, Inc. (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - Dante's Inferno, Canto XXXIV, proofs (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - "The Ice Storm," The New Republic, January 18, 1995, proofs (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - "Ode to Meaning," PN Review III, proofs (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - "On 'Eve Tempted by the Serpent'...," PN Review III, proofs (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - 'On "Sailing to Byzantium,"' proofs (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - "Serpent Knowledge," War Literature and the Arts, Spring 1995, proofs (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - untitled, American Poetry Review, proofs (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - Paris Review interview (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Subseries: Sadness and Happiness: Early
    - Poems--A: "Old Versions, etc." (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Poems deleted after A (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Poems--B (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Poems--C (incomplete) (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Poems deleted after C (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Poems--D (incomplete) (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - This: Poems & Epigrams (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Against Weather: Poems & Epigrams (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Poems deleted after Against Weather (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Dr. Frolic--A (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Poems deleted after Dr. Frolic--A (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Dr. Frolic--B (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Dr. Frolic--C (incomplete) (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Dr. Frolic--D (incomplete) (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Poems deleted after Dr. Frolic--D (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Dr. Frolic--E (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Poems deleted after Dr. Frolic--E (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Tables of Contents for Cold Wide River (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Cold Wide River--A (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Poems delete after Cold Wide River--A (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Cold Wide River--B (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Poems deleted after Cold Wide River--B (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Ten Poems (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Subseries: Sadness and Happiness: Draft
    - Submission records for Sadness And Happiness poetry (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Quote by Pinsky from jacket cover (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Table of Contents, Acknowledgments, and Title Page (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Notes and drafts:I."The Time of Year, The Time of Day" (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Notes and drafts:,II."Sadness And Happiness" (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Notes and drafts:III."Persons" (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Notes and drafts:,IV."The Street of Furthest Memory" (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Sources for V. "Essay on Psychiatrists" (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Notes and drafts: V. "Essay on Psychiatrists" (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Partial draft (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Complete draft (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Bound draft, 3/30/74 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Bound draft, 3/30/74 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Bound draft, 3/30/74 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Bound draft, 3/30/74 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Deleted poems (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Bound draft, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Deleted poems (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Bound draft, blue (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Deleted poems (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Bound draft, revised 2/75 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Bound draft, revised 2/75(copy) (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Bound original typescript (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Typesetter's copy (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Author's proofs, V. "Essay on Psychiatrists" (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Subseries: An Explanation of America
    - Miscellaneous source material (incl. correspondence from "Ann & David") (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Fragmentary notes (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Drafts of Table of Contents and Acknowledgments (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - "Lair" (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Notes and drafts,One, I--"Prologue: You" (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Notes and drafts, One, II--"From the Surface" (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Notes and drafts,One, III--"Local Politics" (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Notes and drafts,One, IV--"Countries and Explanations" (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Notes and drafts,Two, I--"A Love of Death" (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Notes and draftsTwo, II--"Bad Dreams" (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Notes and drafts,Two, III--"Horace, Epistulae I, xvi" (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Notes and draftsTwo, IV--"Filling the Blank" (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Notes and drafts,Three, I--"Braveries" ("The Lesson") (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Notes and draftsThree, II--"Serpent Knowledge" (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Notes and drafts,Three, III---"Mysteries of the Future" (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Notes and draftsThree, IV--"Epilogue: Endings" (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - "Memorial" (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Drafts of Parts One and Two (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Complete draft: "To My Daughter Nichole, age 7" (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Complete draft:"To My Daughter Nichole, age 8" (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Complete draft:"A Poem to My Eldest Daughter" (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Final reading version (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Bound final reading version (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Bound final reading version (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Bound final reading version (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Bound final reading version (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Typesetter's copy (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Author's proof: "from "An Explanation of America'" (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Subseries: Translations
    - Christov, Boris: "Body" typescript (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Christov, Boris: "Spirit," typescript (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Dante's Inferno: drafts, typescript, holograph (Box 21, Folder 8)